lakeshorelearning.com 2016-11-11

# privacy & security at Lakeshore Learning

privacy & security

| 

Here at Lakeshore, we realize that you are concerned about protecting your online privacy. When you shop with us, you can rest assured that your privacy will be respected. We share your concerns. We are dedicated to protecting your privacy and handling any personal information we obtain from you with care and respect. Our Privacy Policy is designed to answer your questions regarding online privacy and security.  
  
---|---  
  
What personal information about customers does Lakeshore gather?  
Lakeshore does not require anyone to share any personal information about themselves in order to view any of our websites. That means you can visit our sites without any need to register with us. However, most of our sites contain special sections and privileges for users who do register.

We may collect personal information from you, such as your name, e-mail address, postal address, phone number, credit card number, gender, birthday, personal interests, etc., when you visit one of our websites or stores, place an order online or by phone, make an in-store purchase, save your information with us online, contact us with a question or concern, or participate in a contest, promotion, or survey. We maintain a record of your product interests and the purchases you make in our stores, online, or by phone and catalog. We also collect information—such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP address”), your browser type, your operating system, and other technical information—from or about the devices you use to access our websites, or when you connect to our in-store Wi-Fi services. If you use different devices to access our sites, such as your home computer, laptop, and/or mobile device, we may be able to associate each of your devices with your account. We may combine all of this information with information about you that we acquire from your activities in our stores or on our sites and/or information we receive from our joint marketing partners and unrelated third parties.

When you sign up to receive text messages, we collect your mobile telephone number in order to send you the text messages. To find out more about our Short Message Service (SMS) text message policies, click here.

When you submit product reviews on our websites, Lakeshore and/or our business partner that operates the review platform will collect personal information from you such as e-mail address, location information, and age and gender. If you provide feedback on any of our products and services, we may use your feedback for any purpose. We will collect any information contained in your communication and will treat the personal information in the communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Consent  
By submitting your personal information to us, either through our websites, in our stores, or by other means, you are agreeing to the collection and storage of your personal information. When you submit this information to us, it means that you have agreed to this Privacy Policy and any updates, and that you expressly consent to the use of your personal information according to this Privacy Policy. You also expressly consent to the sharing of your personal information with our third-party service providers.

How does Lakeshore use your personal information?  
As more fully detailed below, Lakeshore and Lakeshore’s business partners obtain and keep personal information when you send us an e-mail, order product, purchase product, sign up for our customer loyalty program(s), supply information to our Career Center, or otherwise communicate with Lakeshore.

Lakeshore may use your personal information to process and fulfill your order (including to send you e-mails to confirm your order status and shipment); administer our contests and other promotions; and communicate with you and send you information by e-mail, postal mail, telephone, text message, or other means about our products, services, contests, and promotions. Additionally, your personal information helps us better understand your shopping needs and preferences and provide consistent, personalized services and experiences.

We may share your personal information with carefully selected companies whose offers you may be interested in. We also occasionally obtain names, e-mail addresses, and mailing addresses from these companies. Your phone number is not shared with outside companies.

Our web server will automatically collect standard anonymous information (such as web log data and IP addresses). This information helps us spot trends, improve our products and product design, protect the security of our websites, enhance your shopping experience, and improve the functionality of our websites.

Like all retail websites, we use cookies to store your preferences and to help us remember you as a user when you make return visits to our websites. We also use cookies to record session information such as items saved to your shopping cart(s), the different web pages you view on our websites, and the last website you visited prior to visiting ours. We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests. To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising, [click here](http://dtmc.lakeshorelearning.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=3110&cname=Lakeshore%20Learning&cmagic=e9fb2e&clogo=3110.png&loc=us&lang=en-us).

We may engage the services of third parties to collect and use anonymous information about your visits to and interactions with our websites through the use of technologies such as cookies to personalize advertisements for goods and services. To learn more, or to opt out of receiving online display advertisements tailored to your interests by our third-party partners, visit the Network Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

Some third parties involved in advertising operations may maintain their own proprietary consumer databases that allow them to personally identify or track website visitors. Other third parties have proprietary technologies to determine what additional devices you may use, on which they can display relevant advertisements.

Our disclosure of your personal information  
When you purchase a product or a service from our websites, or special-order a product or service from our stores, Lakeshore may share personal information with third-party fulfillment companies in order to deliver the product or service to you. We also share your personal information with third-party service providers that provide advertising and marketing services for Lakeshore, including distribution of postal mail, electronic alerts, e-mail, electronic advertisements, and mobile text messages to you and potential customers. These third-party service providers are required not to use your personal information, except to provide the services requested by Lakeshore, and they are bound by confidentiality agreements for their use of your personal information.

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your personal information, we may disclose your personal information if we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with laws or to respond to subpoenas or other judicial orders served on us, or (b) to protect and defend the rights or property of Lakeshore or third parties.

To provide offers that are of interest to you, we may allow other companies to place advertisements on our websites. As a result of your visit to our websites, advertisement server companies may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address, and clickstream information.

We may also use and disclose personal information for fraud detection and prevention. Personal information and device identification information may be combined with information from other sources and used by us, or by a third party retained by us, to help detect and prevent fraud, credit card fraud, or other illegal or illegitimate activity. All or part of your personal information or device identification information may be kept by us or by the third parties involved in fraud detection and used in future fraud prevention efforts. Information that is believed to be fraudulent may be shared with other retailers, banks, and law enforcement to help prevent illegitimate activity.

Social network widgets  
Our websites may include social network or other third–party plug-ins and widgets that may provide information to their associated social networks or third parties about your interactions with our web pages that you visit, even if you do not click on or otherwise interact with the plug-in or widget. Information is transmitted from your browser and may include an identifier assigned by the social network or third party; information about your browser type, operating system, device type, and IP address; and the URL of the web page where the plug-in or widget appears. If you use social network tools or visit social networking sites, you should read their privacy disclosures, to learn what information they collect, use, and share.

How can I change my personal information?  
At any time, you can review and modify the information you gave us during the registration process. Just go to the your account page. There, you have the option of looking over the information that you gave us and changing or updating that information if desired. We will remove your name from the list we provide to outside companies if you contact us at [lakeshore@lakeshorelearning.com](mailto:lakeshore@lakeshorelearning.com) or call us at (800) 428-4414.

When you receive sales flyers, advertisements, direct mail, and other promotional communications from us, including e-mail, you will have the opportunity to “opt out” by following the “unsubscribe” instructions in the e-mail you receive, or by contacting us directly. Once you have submitted your e-mail address to “unsubscribe,” please note that you may continue to receive e-mails for a time while our system updates your request.

If you have any questions about our websites or our privacy & security policies, send an e-mail to [lakeshore@lakeshorelearning.com](mailto:lakeshore@lakeshorelearning.com).

How will I be notified if your Privacy Policy changes?  
We may amend our Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes in the way we collect or use your personal information, we will notify you by sending you an e-mail at the last e-mail address you provided us, and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our websites.

Click here to view our previous Privacy Policy.

Security  
Shopping online with Lakeshore is a completely safe experience!

We use SSL (Secure Sockets Layer)—the industry standard in online encryption technology—to ensure that your personal and credit card information remains secure. SSL encryption allows you to shop with confidence, knowing that only you and Lakeshore have the ability to access your information.

Our websites have implemented electronic means of protecting your personal information. Even though we have taken steps to ensure that your personal information is not accessed, used, or disclosed by unauthorized persons, you should know that we cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with personal information.

Whenever you access a secure page on our site, the information you send is immediately encrypted for your protection. There are two simple ways to see if you are on a secure page:

• Look at the URL (website address) in your browser. If you are connected to a secure server, the URL will always begin with “https” rather than “http.”  
• Most browsers display an icon that indicates whether or not you have a secure connection.
